莱纳德  如果你明天不忙的话
Hey, Leonard, if you're not busy tomorrow,
我明天下班后有个小活动
I have to do a little reception after work.
我愿意去
Oh, I would,
可我们明天要赶工弄一下空军的项目
but we need to make a push on the air force project.
你确定不来吗
Oh, are you sure?
是要庆祝我们的注意力缺失症新药
We're celebrating our new A.D.D. Drug,
到时候估计六分钟就结束了
and it'll probably be over in, like, six minutes.
你刚才说你们明天要弄导向系统吗
Did you say you guys are working on the guidance system tomorrow?
对啊  怎么了
Yeah, why?
谢尔顿说他明天要跟我一起弄
Well, Sheldon said that he was gonna work with me
我们的量子认知研究呢
on our quantum perception project.
我们一周前就计划好了
We've had this planned for a week.
他今早还跟我重新确认过时间呢
Well, he reconfirmed with me this morning.
两位  在事态开始恶化之前  别忘了
Guys, before this gets ugly, remember,
赢的人得到的可是谢尔顿
the winner gets Sheldon.
拉杰  你明天想跟我一起去吗
Hey, Raj, do you want to go with me tomorrow?
你邀请我是希望我出席  还是可怜我
Are you asking because you want me there or out of pity?
算了  别回答了
Actually, never mind, don't answer.
我愿意去
I'd love to.
大家安安
Hello.
你为什么跟莱纳德说你明天
Why did you tell Leonard you're working on
-要跟他弄陀螺仪的项目  -的确是啊
- the gyroscope tomorrow? - Because I am.
但你答应我要跟我一起做我们的项目
But you said you were working with me.
某人邀了两妞去参加宅男舞会呢
Someone's got two dates to the nerd prom.
山人自有妙计  我有办法同时做两个项目
I have a plan to work on both projects simultaneously.
顺便告诉你  加州理工学院的
And for your information, the summer conference
代数拓扑夏季大会才是真的宅男舞会呢
on algebraic topology at Caltech is nerd prom.
抱歉  不知阁下有何妙计
I'm sorry, what is this plan you have?
我不需要同时出现在两个地方啊
Well, I'm not needed at both places at the same time.
我用些简单小技巧就能腾出几小时
And I can also free up extra hours with simple tricks,
比如表达意见时做到言简意赅
such as using a minimal amount of words to convey my point.
你什么时候能开始这样
When does that start?
快
Soon.
你看  我本来可以说"快开始了"
See, I could've said "In the near future,"
但我没有说"快开始了"
but I didn't say "In the near future,"
因为"快开始了"比"快"多了3个字
'cause "In the near future" is three more words than "Soon."
"快"是1  "开"是2  "始"是3  "了"是4
"In" one, "the" two, "near" three, "future" four.
"快开始了"4个字  而"快"是1个字
See "In the near future" is four, "Soon" is just one,
1字比4字少  所以就省下了时间
four is more than one; saving time already.
天才
Genius.
我本来想说
I was gonna say,
"为什么会有人觉得谢尔顿是天才"
"Why does anyone think Sheldon's a genius?"
但我没说出全部
But I didn't.
先生们  我帮艾米开好头了
Gentlemen, I've got Amy up and running.
我们该开始了吗
Shall we get to work?
在开始前我想问  你背着什么啊
Uh, before we do, what are you wearing,
我们假装你一切正常的这位朋友
oh, friend who we pretend is normal?
这是补水背包
These are hydration backpacks.
为了效率  这包在我口渴时
Eh, for efficiency, whenever I'm thirsty,
能让我直接补充水分
I have access to water.
而当我饿了时  我有扁豆汤
Eh, when I'm hungry, I have lentil soup.
越来越装不下去了
It's getting harder to pretend.
谢尔顿  我们现在到了这决策点
Anyway, Sheldon, we're at a decision point
是让氙气流通过低温制冷机
to run the xenon stream through the cryocooler
还是通过真空过滤器
or through the vacuum filter.
说说看两者的优缺点
Run down the pros and cons of each for me.
如果我们让氙气流通过低温制冷机
Well, if we run the xenon stream through the cryocooler,
它会立即冷却  不会跟导管起反应
it'll be cooled immediately before it reacts with the conduction.
抱歉  胡萝卜丁卡着了
Oh, sorry, uh, carrot chunk.
节省时间的感觉太强烈了
You can just feel the time being saved.
我回来啦  我可以在这八分钟
Ah, I'm back, you got me for eight minutes.
谢尔顿  这样太蠢了
Sheldon, this is silly.
你这样进进出出
You can't expect us to do quality work
我们怎么有办法做出高质量的成果
with you popping in and out like this.
系数不是Λ是Λ₁
The coefficient isn't lambda, it's lambda sub one.
而这边  你应该考虑一下
And over here, you should consider the possibility
大脑本身处于两种不同量子态的可能性
that the brain itself is in two different quantum states.
最后问一下  你有配汤小饼干吗
And lastly, do you have any little soup crackers?
中央轴离心机的旋转速度
The rate of spinning for the central axis centrifuge
必须是每秒钟4转
has to be four revolutions per second.
怎么会是每秒钟4转  必须得是7转
It can't be four revolutions, it's got to be seven.
7个鬼
Seven?!
看清楚了  必须是4转
Look at the board, it's four.
天啊  是7转好吗
Oh, my God, it's seven!
-4转  -7转
- Four! - Seven!
是5.5转
It's five and a half.
我了个去  还真是5.5转
Son of a bitch, it's five and a half.
马回  就是"马上回来"的缩写
B.R.B., that's short for "Be right back."
我省下了好多时间啊
I'm saving so much time!
两个信号在脑胼胝体相遇
The two signals meet up in the corpus callosum
而T=0
and T equals zero.
而我知道某个小男孩值得嘉奖一口汤
And I know a boy who just earned a slurp of soup.
太厉害了
Incredible.
谢尔顿  我原以为你无法同时兼顾两项目
Sheldon, I didn't expect that you could work on both projects,
但我真是大错特错啊
but I, I was wrong.
我一开始也对插勺有这种感觉
You know, I felt the same way about the spork.
一种餐具就想一次解决干的跟稀的
Uh, solids and liquids handled by one utensil?
怎么能行呢
That'll never work.
剧透警告  真的能行
And spoiler: works.
不得不承认
I got to admit,
我们本来并不觉得你能同时兼顾两边
we didn't think you'd be able to do two things at once.
我一开始也对鸭嘴兽有这种看法
Yeah, I felt the same way about the platypus.
禽类与哺乳类合而为一的物种
You know, bird and mammal in the same creature?
怎么能呢
No way.
剧透警告  真的能
And spoiler: way.
再一次谢谢你昨晚借我用你电脑
Oh, thanks again for letting me use your laptop last night.
没事
No problem.
我就是上网报个税
Was just doing my taxes.
好
Okay.
其实要是我能...
Actually, if I could...
要是我能再查看一下...
if I could just check one more...
我已经把浏览器历史记录删了
Already cleared the browser history.
你真是个懂事的好女人
You're a good woman.
你在忙什么
What you working on?
在回去上班前  看看办公室的电邮往来记录
Trying to catch up on office e-mails before I go back.
对哦  你的产假快休完了
Oh, that's right, maternity leave's almost over.
要上班了你兴奋吗
Ah, you excited?
当然  我是说我肯定会想哈雷
Yeah, I mean, I'll miss Halley,
但这样也挺好  可以走出家门
but it'll be nice to get out of the house,
活动活动脑子
be intellectually stimulated.
出去吃午餐  而不是当别人的午餐
Go out to lunch instead of, you know, be lunch.
不错啊  这样挺好的
That's great, good for you.
是啊  反正有你和我爸妈
Yeah, I mean, with you and my parents,
她会没事的
she's gonna be fine.
那是当然
Ah, of course she is.
那家托儿所也不错
And that day care is great.
的确  我特地去查看过
It is. I went to check it out,
他们对于没孩子的陌生人从窗户偷窥这一点
and they are very cautious about letting strange men with no kids
表现出非常警惕的态度
peek in the windows.
再说了  我觉得我给哈雷树立了很好的榜样
Plus, I, I think I'm setting a good example for Halley,
让她知道女人就算当了妈
to show her that women can be mothers
仍可以拥有令人满意的事业
and still have satisfying careers.
当然她不会知道我去了哪  我还会不会回来
Sure, she won't know where I went or if I'm ever coming back.
等我回到家她还有十分钟就要睡觉了
That'll just make the ten minutes between when I get home
于是那十分钟变得更弥足珍贵
and her bedtime even more special.
除了帮你拍奶嗝和给你个奶瓶外
Uh, other than burp you or give you a bottle,
我真不知道该怎么办了
I don't know what to do right now.
没事  我情绪过于激动了
It's okay, I'm just being emotional about this.
拜托别告诉霍华德好吗
Can you not tell Howard?
你不觉得告诉他你怎么了
Well, don't you think it'd be healthier
更有利于你身心健康吗
if you told him what's going on with you?
那你不觉得作为一个成年人
Don't you think it'd be healthier
拥有自己的公寓更有利于你的身心健康吗
if you had your own apartment, grown man?
我会替你保密的
Your secret is safe with me.
你什么时候开始周四洗衣服了
Hey, since when do you do laundry on a Thursday?
我今天上班出了点意外
Oh, I had an accident at work,
我脚一滑  摔到我的汤袋上了
I slipped and fell on my soup sack.
曾几何时  我会问"什么是汤袋"
You know, there was a time I would say "What's a soup sack?"
但...我很高兴多嘴时光已过去了
But... I'm glad we're past that.
曾几何时  我会说"愿神保佑你"
You know, there was a time I would say "God bless you,"
而你会说  "如果你一定要祈求虚构的神灵保佑
and then you would say "If you must invoke an imaginary deity,
求雷神索尔怎么样"
how about Thor?"
于是我会说
And I would say,
"你怎么知道我说的不是雷神"
"How do you know I didn't mean Thor?"
然后你会说"说得好"
And then you would say "Touche,"
而从那刻起
and that there ends the tale
"愿神保佑你"这话与我从此是路人
of why I no longer say "God bless you."
咱俩这一来一往的时光也挺美  不是吗
Well, we have had some fun, haven't we?
是的
Oh, yeah.
莱纳德跟我说你忙得像只陀螺
So, Leonard tells me you've had a busy day.
没错
Oh, I did.
现在还转着呢
It hasn't stopped.
就我在预浸泡裤子  想把扁豆弄出来的时候
I figured out a solution for our navigation system
我想出了我们导向系统的一个解决方案
while I was pre-soaking lentils out of my pants.
你是不是要生病了
Are you getting sick?
当然不是
Of course not.
我太忙没空生病
I'm too busy to be sick.
你身子挺娇弱的
Well, you're pretty delicate.
或许你不该把自己逼这么紧
Maybe you shouldn't be pushing yourself so hard.
-我好得很  -好吧
- I'm fine. - All right.
那我们就假装你看《冰雪奇缘》
Well, we'll just pretend that you didn't catch a cold
-看到感冒的事没发生  -我...
- watching Frozen. - I...
才没有呢
That didn't happen.
你看《飞屋环游记》的时候还流鼻血了
You also got a nosebleed watching Up.
少废话  快洗你的衣服
Just do your laundry!
斯图尔特  你不用特意做晚饭
Stuart, you didn't have to make dinner.
没事  早上害你不开心我挺不好意思
Yeah, well, I felt bad about upsetting you this morning.
而且老实说  我不太喜欢你做的肉卷
And to be honest, I'm not the biggest fan of your meatloaf.
晚餐吃什么
Hey, what's for dinner?
肉卷
Meatloaf.
好吧
Oh, cool.
斯图尔特做的
Stuart made it.
好哒
Oh, cool.
我在想或许我们可以
Hey, I was thinking maybe we take
周末带哈雷去动物园
Halley to the zoo this weekend,
在你上班前
get in a little family time
享受一点家庭时光
before you go back to work.
听起来不错
Sounds great.
说到这个
Speaking of which,
关于托儿所  我不介意送她去
for day care, it'll be easy for me
但如果你很想送她  我也可以让给你
to drop her off, unless you want to do it.
看来是得我来送了
Hmm, guess it should be me.
我送不了
I can't do it;
他们有我的照片记录在案
they have a picture of me on file now.
你没事吧
You okay?
当然  怎么了
Of course, why?
我不知道  你看起来有点不开心
Well, I don't know, you seem a little upset.
-我没事  -你确定吗
- No, I'm fine. - You sure?
你干嘛觉得人家有事
Why don't you think she's fine?
她的声音听起来没事  她的样子看起来也没事
She sounds fine, she looks fine.
如果我在街上看到她  我一定会说
If I saw her on the street I'd say,
"靠  这妞没事[正点]"
"Damn, that girl's fine!"
谢尔顿  你生病了  躺回床上吧
Sheldon, you're sick, go back to bed.
我没事
I am fine.
给  吃你的吐司
Here, eat your toast.
抱歉
Sorry.
没事  这下黄油都省了
It's okay, now I don't need butter.
或许我是有一点受了风寒
Well, perhaps I am a little under the weather.
但吃点感冒药  喝点茶就没事了
It's nothing a little cold medicine and tea can't fix.
你需要睡眠
You need sleep.
我需要的是去工作
What I need is to get to work.
我不想被你的病菌传染
Well, I don't want your germs around me.
怎么  你牵我的手  亲我的嘴就行
What? You hold my hand, you kiss my mouth,
但我发烧到39度就过界了吗
but you draw the line at 102 fever?
我们的爱情怎么了
What happened to our love?
谢尔顿  你没事吧
Sheldon, are you okay?
怎么回事
What's going on?
我怎么会在这里
How'd I get here?
我也不知道  我们下班回家就看到你在这儿了
I don't know, we came home from work and we found you.
下班回家
Home from work?
现在几点
What time is it?
9点
9:00.
9点了
9:00?!
那8点和7点  还有之前那么多点
W-What happened to 8:00 and 7:00
都到哪儿去了
and all the other o'clocks?
等下  你不记得了吗
Wait, you don't remember?
我记得早上起床
Well, I remember waking up in the morning,
艾米在我胸口抹感冒舒缓膏
Amy rubbing Vicks on my chest.
她的手又冰又糙  像两大块冻土
And her hands were like two frozen chunks of tundra.
然后我吃了点感冒药  就...
I took some cold medicine to...
我吃了感冒药
I took cold medicine.
你来实验室时
You did seem a little loopy
看起来的确有点呆滞
when you showed up at the lab.
实验室
At-- at the lab?!
为什么我的下半身是赤裸的
Why am I naked from the waist down?
我不知道你的裤子在哪里
I don't know where your pants are,
但我们倒是在炉子上的锅里发现你的内裤
but we did find your underwear in a pot on the stove.
我的裤子不见了  我什么都不记得了
My pants are missing, I don't remember anything.
佩妮  你青春在断片中度过  分享下经验
Penny, this is your youth. What do I do?
我不知道
I don't know,
检查一下有没有新纹身吧
check your body for tattoos?
莱纳德  你能不能当个贴心的宝宝...
Leonard, would you be a lamb...
她在逗你的
She's kidding!
等等  我的背包呢
Wait, wait. Where's my bag?
-我的电话跟钱包都在里头  -在这里
- My phone and my wallet are in my bag. - It's right here.
我的笔记本呢  我的笔记本不见了  不要啊
Where's my notebook? My notebook's gone. Oh, no.
不过是本笔记本而已  有什么大不了的
Okay, it's just a notebook, what's the big deal?
有什么大不了的
What's the big deal?
里面全是关于那个空军项目的机密信息
It's full of classified information about the air force project!
你怎么能把那个弄丢了呢
How could you lose that?
没关系  我们一定能找着
It's okay, I'm sure we'll find it.
肯定就在这里的某个角落
Look, it's got to be around here somewhere.
也许跟你的裤子在同个地方
Maybe it's wherever your pants are.
不  裤子在微波炉里  笔记本不在
Nope, pants in the microwave, no notebook.
你好
Ah, hello.
伯纳黛特好像有心事
Look, something's going on with Bernadette.
她有跟你说什么吗
She say anything to you?
一个字都没说
Well, nope, not a word.
别这样  跟我说实话
Come on, be honest.
你是不是告诉她  我偷用过她的吸奶器
Did you tell her I tried her breast pump?
没有  但我倒是跟我的心理医生提过
No, but I did mention it to my therapist.
反正她肯定是在生我的气
Well, I know she's mad at me about something.
你做了什么会惹怒她的事
Well, what have you done that would upset her?
那要看你有多少时间听
Oh, gosh, how much time do you have?
要不你先说最严重的那件事呗
Well, why don't you just start with the worst thing?
我想想啊
Hmm, let's see.
好  来吧  六年前
Okay, here we go: six years ago,
我接到一通电话  说妮妮的姨婆特里克茜去世了
I got a call that Bernie's great-aunt, Trixie, died.
然后呢
And?
然后我忘记转告她
And I forgot to give her the message.
太过分了
That's terrible.
真正过分的是  从那之后
The terrible part is, ever since then,
我以特里克茜的名义
I've been sending Bernie
每年都给妮妮寄圣诞贺卡
Christmas cards from Trixie.
霍华德
Howard!
听我说完  有张贺卡里还夹了五块钱
Let me finish-- and one card had five dollars in it
是我从妮妮的钱包里偷的
I took from Bernie's purse.
笔记本不在浴室里
The notebook isn't in the bathroom.
我也找不到
I can't find it, either.
他怎么能失忆一整天呢
How can he not remember a day?
被外星人掳走过的人会不记得那段时间
Well, people who are abducted by aliens lose time.
可能那也会发生在外星人自己身上吧
I mean, maybe it happens to the aliens, too.
不在对面的屋子里
Well, it's not across the hall.
已成定局了  我违反了保密协议
That's it. I'm in breach of my security clearance.
我要去蹲大牢了
I'm going to prison.
你们也懂我这种可人儿进监狱会有何下场
And you know what happens to people like me in prison.
我会被迫当某位大佬的私人教师
I'll be forced to be some large man's tutor.
你不会进监狱的
You're not going to prison.
可是想想那个画面  还真是乐开怀
But, boy, it is funny to think about.
你真的什么都想不起来吗
You really can't remember anything?
我在想啊
I'm trying.
等等  给我看看你的手机
Wait a minute. Hey, let me see your phone.
为什么
Why?
手机有可能
Well, it's-- it's possible
记录下你去过的所有地方
it was tracking everywhere you went.
手机还有这个功能吗
Phones can do that?
是的  得看你隐私设置了
Yeah, it depends on the privacy settings.
这功能好酷啊
Oh, tha-- that's so cool.
要怎么...  怎么样才能关掉啊
How do you-- how do you turn that thing off?
淡定
Relax.
我知道你"去跑步"时  中途吃了个甜甜圈
I know when you "go for a run," you stop for a donut.
我不是跑过去的  我是开车去的
I don't even run there, I drive.
稍等  我能看到你去过的所有地点了
Hang on, I can see every place you went.
记录怎么说
What does it say?
你在这栋楼里
Uh, you were in the building,
你到过大学
you were at the university,
然后你到了科罗拉多大道上的某处
then you were somewhere on Colorado Boulevard.
哪里
Where?
等等
Wait, hang on.
你有去过牛仔酒吧吗
Did you go to a cowboy bar?
我...怎么可能
I-- no!
太荒谬了
That is preposterous.
有可能
Maybe.
你还好吗
Hey, how's it going?
好啊
Fine.
好吧  爱你哦
Good. Love you.
-我也爱你  -爱你更多
- Love you, too. - Love you more.
行  你赢了  我能继续做事了吗
Okay, you won. Can I finish what I'm doing?
抱歉
Sure, sorry.
你有事吗
Something on your mind?
没  没事
No, no, nothing.
好吧  我只是觉得
Okay, well, maybe I'm just feeling like
你好像有烦心事
something's bothering you.
不  我好着呢
Nope, all good.
为了证明  和我在厨房地板上滚一炮吧
Prove it, make love to me right now on the kitchen floor.
才不要  你脑子有病吧
No, what is wrong with you?
看吧  你就是不开心
Aha, you are upset.
我虽不了解女人  但我知道我让她们不开心了
I don't know a lot about women, but I know I upset them.
霍华德  抱歉我可能举止有点怪
Howard, I'm sorry if I'm being weird,
但这件事和你没有关系
but it has nothing to do with you.
真的跟我无关吗
It doesn't?
没有
No.
我不想告诉你  但是...
I didn't want to tell you, but...
我心里对于回去工作这件事挺不好受
I'm having a really tough time about going back to work.
这样呀  我明白
Okay, well, I get that.
当我陪产假结束时  也很难过
It was hard for me when I went back.
-真的吗  -当然啦
- It was? - Of course.
我万分思念你和宝宝
I missed you and the baby
还有每天能看《艾伦秀》的快乐时光
and being able to watch Ellen every day.
我只是不知道什么才算是正确的选择
I just don't know what the right thing to do is.
如果我回去上班  我就像抛弃了哈雷
If I go back to work, I'm abandoning Halley.
如果我不上班
If I don't go,
那就放弃了我以前奋斗的事业
I'm giving up everything I worked for.
感觉就没有一个正确的选择
It's like there's no right choice.
我也不知道什么才算是正确的选择
Look, I don't know what the best decision is, either.
但不管我们如何做  只要不开心
But whatever we choose, if we're not happy,
那我们就换一种选择
we can undo it.
也许吧
I guess.
而最棒的是  哈雷完全不会记得这些事
And the best part is: Halley won't remember a thing.
宝宝们虽然可爱  但也傻呼呼的
Babies are cute, but they're dumb.
你看  我把脸遮住
I mean, I-I go like this,
她就觉得我不见了  手打开  我又回来了
she thinks I'm gone. Then magically I'm back.
老实说  我们干嘛还费劲给她存大学学费呢
Honestly, why are we saving for college?
我不喜欢你说我们宝宝蠢
I'm not crazy about you calling our baby dumb.
她这点遗传了我
Well, she gets it from me.
说到这个
Speaking of which,
我要告诉你一些特里克茜姨婆的事
I have some news about your Aunt Trixie.
这地方看起来眼熟不
Does this place look familiar?
很难说
It's hard to say.
谢尔顿回来了
Hey, Sheldon's back!
谢尔顿
Sheldon!
我开始回想起一些了
It's getting clearer.
你还要请大家再喝一轮吗
You gonna buy another round for the house?
不  谢谢了
Uh, n-no, thank you.
懂为什么万事达卡给我发异常消费警告了
We now know why MasterCard sent me a fraud alert.
问问他呀
Ask him.
好的
Um, yes.
干哈呢  兄弟
Howdy, partner.
你有没有捡到我在这旮沓
Do you happen to recollect if I left a notebook
掉的一本笔记本啊
in these here parts?
还这旮沓
These here parts?
我这叫融入环境  所以祝你好运吧
It's called fitting in. By the way, good luck.
给你
Here you go.
谢天谢地
Thank goodness!
最高机密量子导向系统
One top secret quantum guidance system.
你能懂里面的数学吗
You understood the math?
不懂  但是谢尔顿详细地给我解释了一遍
No, but Sheldon told me all about it.
他给大伙都解释了一遍
He told everybody.
太好了
That's just great.
别担心
Oh, don't worry,
他让我们拉勾发誓保守秘密了
he made us pinky swear we'd keep it a secret.
我发誓
I swear...
绝不告诉任何人
...not to tell anyone...
这个我要告诉大家的
...the top secret military information
军事绝密
I'm about to tell you.
这个我要告诉大家的
The top secret military information
军事绝密
I'm about to tell you.
我们必须赶紧撤了
We really need to skedaddle.
谢了  再见
Thank you. Bye.
再见
See you.
还是把这个擦了吧
Should probably erase this.
多谢你帮我泡茶
Thank you for making me tea.
不用谢  好喝吗
You're welcome. How is it?
真好喝  还让人家背后也暖暖的
Yummy. And warm on my back.
你还需要什么吗
Do you need anything else?
你知道我需要什么
You know exactly what I need.
好吧
Fine.
♪ 软猫猫  暖猫猫 ♪
♪ Soft kitty, warm kitty, ♪
♪ 小毛球猫猫 ♪
♪ Little ball of fur ♪
♪ 笑猫猫  困猫猫 ♪
♪ Happy kitty, sleepy kitty ♪
♪ 呼噜呼噜呼噜 ♪
♪ Purr, purr, purr. ♪
真好听
That's nice.
用德语唱一遍
Now in German.
♪ 猫咪软软  猫咪暖暖 ♪
♪ Weiches Kätzchen, warmes Kätzchen ♪
♪ 猫咪小毛球 ♪
♪ Ai mi gui che dan ♪
♪ 猫咪萌萌  猫咪累累 ♪
♪ Liebes Kätzchen, müdes Kätzchen ♪
♪ 噗噜噗噜噗噜 ♪
♪ Schnurrt, schnurrt, schnurrt. ♪
真美妙
Great.
用普通话唱
Now Mandarin.
再用纳瓦荷语[印第安语]唱
Now Navajo.